Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
James Britton papers
circa 1905-1984, bulk circa 1905-1935
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Britton, James
2.9 linear feet
The papers of painter and writer James Britton measure 2.9 linear feet and date from circa 1905-1984, with the bulk of the material dating from circa 1905-1935. The bulk of the papers consist of 49 diaries dating from 1918-1935, plus notebooks of diary excerpts, that chronicle Britton's daily activities and include lists, illustrations, and drafts of correspondence. Additional papers include biographical information compiled by the Britton family; scattered business and financial records; correspondence, including copies of Britton's letters to the editors of the Hartford Courant and the Hartford Times; additional writings and notes that include drafts and manuscripts of an autobiography, drafts of articles for his publication Art Opus, and other writings; sketches and a woodcut print; printed materials, including clippings of his published writings for Art Review International, Book Notes, and Opus; and one photograph of Britton and of works of art.
Provenance
James Britton's granddaughters, Barbara Britton and Ursula Roberts Britton donated the James Britton papers in 1985.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of this collection was digitized in 2010 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website. Materials that have not been digitized include photographs of works of art, duplicates, and some printed materials.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
James Britton (1878-1936) was a portrait painter and writer active in Connecticut and New York. Britton wrote extensively about American art and artists and was the editor of his own publications Art Review International and Opus. Also, he was a member of the group of New York painters and sculptors known as The Eclectics.
Born in Hartford, Connecticut in 1878, James Britton began his career as an apprentice working under August Jaccaci at Scribner's Magazine in 1895. He studied under George de Forest Brush at the Art Students' League and under Walter Griffin and Charles Noel Flagg in Hartford. He exhibited and worked with many of the American artists associated with the Ash Can school and The Eclectics, a group of New York artists that included Theresa Bernstein, Guy Pene du Bois, Walter Griffin, Philip L. Hale, Eugene Higgins, George Luks, Jane Peterson, Maurice Prendergast, and Mahonri Young. Mainly, Britton worked as a portrait painter but produced many landscapes of Sag Harbor, Long Island, and of his homes in Connecticut. He was a founding member of the New Society of American Artists and the Connecticut Academy of Fine Arts. He exhibited at numerous New York City galleries including Ainslie Galleries, Arlington Galleries, Babcock Galleries, Dudensing Galleries, Folsom Galleries, and at the studio of sculptor Marie Apel.
A prolific writer on American art and artists, as well as an illustrator, Britton worked as staff artist for the Hartford Times and as an art critic for American Art News and the Hartford Courant. He also founded and edited Art Review International and Opus. Two of his published books include Copley, Painter of the Revolution and Artists of America. Britton was also interested in classical music and wrote on composers Haydn and Beethoven. Britton's extensive diaries found within his papers chronicle his daily life and commentary.
In 1914, Britton married Caroline Korner and settled mostly in Connecticut. They had three children, Jerome, Teresa, and Ruth. In 1928, a car struck Britton and left him disabled. Although he continued to paint, he suffered from ill-health as a result of the accident. He died in 1936.
James Britton's works are represented at the Wadsworth Atheneum, Mark Twain Memorial, Manchester Public Library and at St. Joseph's College.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painter and writer James Britton measure 2.9 linear feet and date from circa 1905-1984, with the bulk of the material dating from circa 1905-1935. The bulk of the papers consist of 49 diaries dating from 1918-1935, plus notebooks of diary excerpts, that chronicle Britton's daily activities and include lists, illustrations, and drafts of correspondence. Additional papers include biographical information compiled by the Britton family; scattered business and financial records; correspondence, including copies of Britton's letters to the editors of the Hartford Courant and the Hartford Times; additional writings and notes that include drafts and manuscripts of an autobiography, drafts of articles for his publication Art Opus, and other writings; sketches and a woodcut print; printed materials, including clippings of his published writings for Art Review International, Book Notes, and Opus; and one photograph of Britton and of works of art.
Biographical information consists of a file of photocopied materials prepared by the Britton Family. Scattered business and financial records include papers relating to Britton's auto accident, indexes of letters, illustrated indexes and lists of works of art, miscellaneous invoices and receipts, and file relating to Arlington Gallery.
Nine folders of correspondence include letters written to and by Britton along with posthumus materials to his widow, Caroline Britton. Correspondents include artists and friends Gertrude Fiske, Eugene Higgins, Kyonei Inukai, Andrew Kelly, Dewitt McClellan Lockman, Edwin Valentine Mitchell, Maurice Prendergast, Duncan Phillips, Alfred Steiglitz, Robert Vonnoh, and Robert C. Vose.
The bulk of the Britton papers consist of his extensive diaries - 49 volumes, plus notebooks of excerpts and detailed indexes. The diaries date from 1918-1935 and details Britton's daily activities and observations about art figures active in New York and Connecticut, classical music, the Great Depression, Prohibition, the Catholic Church, and politics. In addition, Britton talks of his relationships with his wife and children. The diaries served as a place for Britton to make lists of works of art, portrait subjects, potential clients, etc. Britton also created "Notebooks of Diary Excerpts" and a detailed index of many of the diaries.
Additional writings and notes include a handwritten and incomplete typescript of an autobiography, writings for Britton's publication Opus, and miscellaneous writings about art, music and plays. Writings by others include works by Duncan Scott Kent and Blackfield.
Artwork includes a print and sketches by Britton, and children's drawings.
Printed materials include issues of Britton's Art Review International, Opus, and other publications for which he wrote articles or provided illustration, clippings, exhibition catalogs, and programs.
Photographs include one photo of the artist with a painting and photos of works of art.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical Information, 1970-1984 (Box 1; 1 folder)
Series 2: Business and Financial records, 1919-1933 (Box 1; 7 folders)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1913-1945 (Box 1; 9 folders)
Series 4: Diaries, 1918-1935 (Box 1-2; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 5: Writings and Notes, circa 1910s-1931 (Box 2-3; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 6: Artwork, circa 1920-1929 (Box 3; 5 folders)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1910-1982 (Box 4; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, circa 1905-1930s (Box 4, OV 1; 3 folders)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Arlington Galleries (New York, N.Y.)
Subjects-Topical:
Art, Modern -- 20th century -- Connecticut; Art, Modern -- 20th century -- New York (State) -- New York; Art critics; Authors -- New York (State) -- New York; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York -- Diaries; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York
Types of Materials:
Diaries; Drafts; Illustrations; Notebooks; Photographs; Prints; Sketches
Names:
Blackfield; Fiske, Gertrude, 1878-1961; Higgins, Eugene, 1874-1958; Inukai, Kyohei, 1913-; Kelly, Andrew J.; Kent, Duncan Scott; Lockman, DeWitt McClellan, 1870-1957; Mitchell, Edwin Valentine, 1890-1960; Phillips, Duncan, 1886-1966; Prendergast, Maurice Brazil, 1858-1924; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946; Vonnoh, Robert William, 1858-1933; Vose, Robert C. (Robert Churchill), 1911-
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Information, 1970-1984, Series 1:; (Box 1; 1 folder)
  A file of photocopied materials prepared by the Britton family includes correspondence concerning Britton, a list of articles by Britton, and excerpts from reviews written by Britton.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Biographical Information Compiled by Britton Family, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Business and Financial Records, 1919-1933, Series 2:; (Box 1; 7 folders)
  There are scattered records relating to Britton's auto accident including a police report; a gallery tag from Arlington Galleries; an index of letters sent and an address book; illustrated indexes of works of art by Britton in which he drew small representative sketches of his portraits and landscapes; a list of works of art; and various receipts and invoices.
  - Auto Accident, 1928 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gallery Tag--Arlington Gallery, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Index, Letters Sent and Address Book, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Illustrated Index, Works of Art--Portraits, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Illustrated Index, Works of Art--Landscapes, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lists of Works of Art, 1933 May (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Receipts and Invoices, 1919-1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1913-1945, Series 3:; (Box 1; 9 folders)
  This series consists of general correspondence between James Britton and artists and friends as well as correspondence regarding his publications Art Review International and Opus. Also found are copies of Britton's letters to the editors of the Hartford Times and the Hartford Courant. Of note is a draft of a letter written to President Calvin Coolidge urging for the creation of a Secretary of Fine Arts written on another letter dated August 20, 1983. Britton also wrote draft responses on incoming letters. Posthumus letters written to Britton's wife include condolence letters and letters from Katherine Day of the Mark Twain Memorial concerning a donation of Britton's painting of the author.
  Correspondents include Caroline Korner Britton, Gertrude Fiske, Eugene Higgins, Kyonei Inukai, Andrew J. Kelly, DeWitt McClellan Lockman, Edwin Valentine Mitchell, Maurice Prendergast, Duncan Phillips, Alfred Stieglitz, Robert Vonnoh, and Robert C. Vose.
  - 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1920-1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1925-1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Undated, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters to the Editor, Hartford Courant, circa 1930-1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters to the Editor, Hartford Times, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Diaries, 1918-1935, Series 4:; (Box 1-2; 1.5 linear feet)
  James Britton detailed his thoughts, work, and other activities in 49 diaires. He also created 10 notebooks of diary excerpts and a detailed index of subjects and names found in the diaries.
  The Diaries series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  Subseries 4.1: Diaries, 1918-1935
  Subseries 4.2: Notebooks of Diary Excerpts, 1918-1934
  This series has been scanned in its entirety, except for one incomplete draft diary index created by Britton, which was superceded by a later index.
  - Diaries, 1918-1935, Subseries 4.1:
    Britton's diaries cover a wide-range of subjects including current affairs and his thoughts about American art and artists, the art scene in New York and Connecticut, classical music, the Great Depression, Prohibition, the Catholic Church, politics, his artwork and writings, his professional associations, New York galleries and exhibitions, and his relationships with family and friends. The diaries also include lists and sketches, including sketches of paintings in his studio at the time of the diary entry. The diaries provide an intimate and descriptive perspective of the Great Depression and its effect on the American family. Hard economic times forced Britton to reuse his children's school composition notebooks as diaries, often writing in the margins or in between the original lines of writing. He describes the toll of the economy on his relationship with his family.
    The diaries contain exhaustive detail about the New York art scene and his fellow artists. He writes about George Bellows, Childe Hassam, Ernest Blumenschein, among many others, and about visiting numerous galleries, museums, and exhibitions, such as Knoedler, Frank Rehn, and Kraushaar Galleries, as well as his membership in various clubs and associations, including the New Society of American Artists.
    There are two numbered sets of diaries. The first set is numbered XXV-XL and the second set is numbered Miscellanous Volumes 1-32. Britton also created a two-volume index of his diaries numbered XXV-XL. Most of the index was transcribed by the processing archivist and a partial list of relevant name/subject entries is found with the link to each individual diary. A more comprehensive list of entries from Britton's index is also included as an addendum.
    A Volume XXX B is referenced in Britton's index which does not appear to be in the collection. It may be missing or perhaps the number was changed by Britton at a later date.
    The narrative summaries and access points included with the Miscellaneous Volumes 1-32 were created by the processing archivist and should not be considered fully comprehensive.
    See Addendum List of Names and Subjects for Diaries XXV-XL from Series 4.1.
    This subseries has been scanned in its entirety.
    Addendum List of Names and Subjects from Diary Volumes XXV-XL in Series 4.1.
    Adams, Herbert: XXVII, 88
    Ainslie, George: XXXI, 66, 94; XXXII, 38-39; XXXV, 59; XXXVIII, 9, 28, 33
    Aitken, Robert J: XXXI, 38-40, 44, 46; XXXV, 7-8, 20, 43; XXXVI, 23
    Alexander, Francis: XXXVI, 2
    Allen, Ted: XXXVII, 29
    Andrews, Helen: XXIX, 68
    Anderson, Karl: XXVII, 116
    Anderson, Oscar: XXV, 64, 71, 103-106, 119; XXVI, 28; XXXV, 16
    Anderson, Ruth: XXXVIII, 30
    Anisfeld, Boris: XXVI 48-5l; XXVII; XXXI, 93
    Apel, Marie: XXV, 52; XXVI, 44, 47, 57, 97-99; XXIX, 40, 70
    Armistice: XXVI, 64-68, 76
    Arndt, Paul: XXIX, 70
    Art News: XXXVIII, 73
    Art Review International: XXVII, 1, 59; XXXIII, list
    Atwood, William E: XXV, 50, 53, 56, 62-63, 67-70, 88, 90; XXVI, 28
    Auerbach-Levy, William: XXV, 73, 80
    Avery, Milton: XXIX, 54
    Babcock, E.C.; XXVI, 85, 90, 102-3, 112, 117, 123, 127; XXVII, 38, 41, 49, 73, 80; XXXI, 66-8, 72; XXXV, 60, 108
    Ballerini, Nicolo: XXXI, 47; XXXVI, 15-7
    Bannon, Annie: XXV, 4; XXVII, 118; XXIX, 52; XXX, 12; XXXI, 13, 75-6, 93; XXXII, 34; XXIV, 1, 138
    Baker, Bryant: XXV, 51, 56, 62, 83, 88, 92
    Barile, Xavier J.: XXXI, 95; XXXII, 46; XXXV, 124; XXXVII, 29
    Barry, James: XXVI, 82; XXIX, 32; XXX, 18; XXXI, 28; XXXIV, 84, self portrait
    Bartlett, Paul: XXVII, 65, 90, 109; XXX, 20; XXXII, 1, 34-5; XXXV, 7, 20
    Bayley, Frank [Copley Gallery]: XXV, 70, 101-102; XXIX, 4-5, 59
    Beal, Gifford: XXVII, 28, 61, 70; XXXI, 76-80; XXXV, 117
    Bean, Caroline: XXVII, 49; XXXVI, 14
    Beaux, Cecelia: XXVII, 54, 69, 119; XXXIII, 2
    Beckwith, Carrol: XXIX, 1
    Bellows, George: XXV, 84; XXVI, 41-6, 187; XXVII, 114-117; XXXIX, 6, 70; XXX, 12; XXXII, 46; XXXV, 43; XXXV B, 2, 3, 6; XXXVII, 49, 100; XXXI, 52, 73; XXXII, 46; XXXIII, 8; XXXVII, 14
    Belcher, Hilda: XXXVIII, 29
    Bernstein, Teresa: XXV, 38, 50-5, 69, 80, 90-105; XXVI, 44-6, 58-9, 63, 80-4, 90-2, 104, 133
    Betts, Louis: XXVII, 25
    Birch Miniature: XXVII
    Blakelock, R.A.: XXX, 27, 42-3, 46; XXXIV, 37; XXXV, 78
    Blashfield, Edwin H.: XXVI, 42
    Booth, Ralph H.: XXV, visits Gloster exhibit, 80
    Borglum, Gutzon: XXX, 20
    Boswel, Peyton: XXVI, 98; XXXIII, 16
    Bouche, Louis: XXXVII, 25
    Boucher, Dr.: XXV, 3, 103-106; XXXI, 76
    Bowdoin, W.G.: XXVI, 47-8, 62, 91, 103, 123; XXVII, 69; XXXI, 2; XXXIII, 2; XXXVI, 26-7
    Brandegee, Robert B.: XXV, 70; XXVI, 31, 62; XXVII, 43, 57, 118-19; XXIX, 2, 44, 68, 72; XXXVII, 24
    Brennan, Alfred
    Britton, Caroline: XXV, 32; XXVII, 49; XXXIV, 22, 31; XXXVIII, 61
    Britton, Dr. Christian: XXVI, 48, 50-2, 60, 86, 117; XXVII, 32, 115-117; XXX, 3-4; XXXI, 92; XXXIII, 30; XXXIV, 15; XXXVI, 26
    Britton, Ernest J.: XXVI, 39; XXIX, 44, 52; XXX12, XXXI, 7-13; XXXI, 50, 92; XXXII, 32-33; XXXIII
    Britton, Jerome: XXV, 37; XXXVIII, 32, 35
    Britton, Captain J.C.: XXV, 3; XXVI, 2, 29, 43; XXVII, 114; XXIX, 2, 44, 52, 74; XXXI, 12, 50, 65-71; XXXV, 9-11
    Britton, Mrs. J.C.: XXV, 3, 25
    Britton, Leo F.: XXXI, 76
    Britton, Ruth: XXX; XXXVIII, 54, 63
    Britton, Teresa: XXV, 61; XXVI, 115; XXVII, 110
    Brooks, Richard: XXV, 55, 71
    Brown, Frank L.: XXV, 71, 92
    Brown, Henry Kirke: XXXIII, 37
    Bruno, Guido: XXVII, 110
    Brush, Franklin: XXV, 56, 63, 97, 105-7, 137
    Brush, George de Forest: XXXIII, 2
    Buchanan, Charles L: XXVII, 42
    Bunce, W. Gedney: XXVII, 46, 48, 71-2; XXXV, 6, 120
    Burr, Colin: XXIX, 5
    Burrows, Carlyle: XXXVII, 29; XXXVIII, 10, 31, 72
    Buttero, Arturo: XXXVI, 24, 45
    Caffin, Charles H.: XXVII, 80
    Cameron, D.Y.: XXIX
    Capone, Gaetano: XXVI, 100
    Caprio, V.D.: XXXV, 42, 45, 94-5
    Carlsen, Enid: XXIX, 5, 72; XXXI, 27, 76, 77, 82; XXXIII, 1-2; XXXVI, 68; XXXV B, 7
    Carroll, John: XXXIII, 20-4; XXXV, 32, 34, 45, 64, 89-90, 106-7, 212, 127, 135-6; XXXCIII, 12, 17
    Cary, Elizabeth Luster: XXVI, 95; XXVII, 79; XXXI, 67, 82; XXXVII, 13, 16
    Cezanne, Paul: XXXV B, 6
    Chapman, Carlton: XXIX, 59; XXX, 4-5
    Chase, William M.: XXV, 96; XXVII, 64, 68; XXXVIII, 3
    Chasseriau: XXX, 32
    Chavannes, Purvis de: XXV, 56
    Cheney, Russell: XXXVI, 26-7, 75-6; XXXVIII, 18
    Clark, Eliot: XXVII, 99, 100; XXX, 5
    Clarke, Thomas B: XXVI, 115; XXVII, 87, XXIX, 48, XXX, 8
    Clivette, Merton: XXXVI, 48-50
    Coburn, F.W.: XXV, 62, 67, 92
    Cole, Thomas Casilear: XXXV, 77, 120, 123, 126, 131, 136; XXXVI, 82, 85; XXXVIII, 14, 33
    Cooney, Mrs Anna P Britton Macgronen: XXVI, 39; XXVII, 43, 57, 91, 111, 115; XXIX, 43, 55; XXXI, 72; XXXV, 5, 31; XXXV B, 27; XXXVI, 6
    Cooney, John: XXV, 21, 39; XXVI, 58, 115; XXVII, 42; XXIX, 49, 55; XXXI, 73-6; XXXII, 5; XXXV, 114, 125; XXXVI, 6, 9-10, 28, 39; XXXVI, 48, 61, 71, 88; XXXV B, 27
    Cooney, Michael: XXXI, 92
    Copley, John Singleton: XXV, 29, 50, 61-2, 65, 70, 73, 77-8, 86, 102-3, 108, 113, 115-17; XXVI, 57, 81-2, 106, 109-12, 111-122, 129; XXVII, 1, 3, 17-8, 29, 35, 93; XXIX, 4; XXX, 35, 44-6; XXXI, 36; XXXII, 8-9; XXXIII, 4, 17, 26, 32, 34, 46, 80, 84-5, 87, 99; XXXVI, 2, 34; XXXVII, 12; XXXVIII, 51; XXXIX; XL, 1-2
    Coppedge, Fern: XXV, 95
    Cornoyer, Paul: XXV, 71
    Cortissoz, Royal: XXVI, 102, 134; XXXIII, 9; XXXV, 111
    Costigan, John: XXVIII, 3
    Cosway, Richard: XXV, 115
    Cox, Kenyon: XXVII, 7, 97
    Crane, Bruce: XXX, 38-40
    Crews, Floyd: XXXV, 36, 60, 90, 94, 114, 122-4, 136-7; XXXVI, 23-5, 37, 46, 86; XXXV B, 5, 9, 18-9; XXXVII, 22; XXXVIII, 13, 33-4; XXXIX, 1
    Cross, Amy: XXXV, 116
    D'Hervilly: XXXV, 29
    Damrosch, Helena: XXXV, 134
    Daniel, Charles: XXVI, 98, 134; XXVII, 26, 99; XXIX, 39, 42; XXIX, 56; XXXI, 84-6; XXXVII, 16; XXXVIII, 3
    Davey, Randell: XXV, 54, 69, 73, 80-1, 84-89, 95-100, 106; XXVI, 29, 40, 99-100; XXVII, 27, 38
    Davies, A.B.: XXVII, 84, 87-8
    Davis, Ch. H.: XXXIV, 2
    De Nezzo, Victor: XXXI, 65; XXXIII, 10
    De Valera, Eamon: XXIX, 81; XXX, 1, 11; XXXI; XXXIII, 2; XXXV, 19, 135; XXXVI, 53
    DeCamp, Jos: XXXIII, 14
    DeKay, Charles: XXX, 39
    DeMorgan, William: XXXVIII, 47
    Detweiller, F.: XXVI, 97, 119, 123-5, 130-4; XXXVI, 6, 20-1, 37, 54-5, 77-8, 80-2, 85-7; XXXV B, 20; XXXVII, 22, 29, 32-8; XXXVIII, 14, 49, 52, 81, 88-9; XXXIX, 5
    Dewey, Ch. Melville: XXIX, 72
    Dickinson, Edwin: XXVII, 94; XXXVIII, 31, 42, 94
    Dickinson, S.E.: XXVI, 48, 90, 125-7, 133; XXVII, 40-1, 51, 56-8, 63-4, 70, 73-9, 91, 93; XXVII, 93-7, 107-9; XXIX, 36, 40, 64, 70-1; XXX, 2, 38, 45, 47, 51, 61, 72-5, 82, 94; XXXII, 5, 32-3; XXXIII, 7, 10, 23-5; XXXIV, 1, 3-4; XXXV. 6, 36, 38, 55-6, 74, 77, 90, 93-4, 105-6, 115, 121-2; XXXV B, 17, 20-5; XXXVI, 5, 7, 11, 30, 36, 44, 55-6, 71, 90, 83; XXVII, 1; XXXVIII; XXXIX
    Donner, Herman Montago: XXXVI, 18
    Donoghue, John: XXXII, 1
    Donohue, William Howard: XXXVIII, 49; XXXIX, 3-4
    Dorfner, Joseph: XXXV, 132, 136
    Dorr, C. H.: XXXVI, 102; XXXVII, 78, 90
    Dougherty, Paul: XXXVI, 103, 142; XXXVII, 33-4, 70; XXX, 3, 17; XXXVII, 72
    Douglas, H. W.: XXVII, 119; XXIX, 11, 64, 68
    Downes, W.H.: XXV, 28
    Downey, Chris: XXXV, 29
    Dreier, Katherine: XXXVIII, 89
    DuBois, Guy Pene: XXV, 85, 91; XXVI, 40, 89-91; XXVII, 53, 69, 74, 79, 100; XXIX, 72; XXXI, 62; XXXII, 6; XXXV, 117
    Dudensing: XXXI, 46, 78; XXXII, 40, 46; XXXV, 99, 121-2; XXXVI, 88; XXXV B, 17, 21; XXXVII, 13, 24; XXXVIII, 8, 10, 17, 33, 49, 52, 88-9, 92, 94, 100, 105
    Dunlap, William: XXXV, 84-6
    Duveen: XXVIII, 9
    Duveneck, Frank: XXV, 53, 86; XXVI, 48; XXIX, 57; XXXI, 67; XXXIII, 1; XXXV, 61
    Eakins, Thomas: XXVII, 67; XXXV, 111; XXXVI, 21; XXXV B, 6
    Eaton, Alfred J.: XXXV, 21
    Eilshemius, Louis: XXXVIII, 89
    Eitel, Walter O.: XXV, 48, 103; XXVI, 100; XXVIII, 104
    Ehrich, Walter: XXIX, 10, 55
    Elliott, C. L.: XXX, 26
    Ennis, George Pearse: XXVII, 38, 96; XXIX, 6; XXXI, 79; XXXIII, 7; XXXV, 131; XXXVIII, 9
    Escobal: XXXVII, 42
    Expressionists: XXVII, 50, 73
    Fairchild, May: XXXVI, 63; XXXVIII, 30; XXXVII
    Fenning, Elizabeth: XXIX, 54
    Feurbach, Anselm: XXIX, 41
    Fiedler, Max: XXXVI, 17
    Fiske, Gertrude: XXVI, 127
    Fitler, Mrs. W.C. Claude Raquet Hirst: XXV, 54; XXVII, 62; XXXVIII, 30
    Flagg, Charles Noel: XXVII, 71; XXIX, 41, 45; XXXII, 34; XXXV B, 5, 18
    Flagg, Montague: XXIX, 34; XXXV B, 18, 23; XXXVIII, 20
    Flanagan, John: XXVII, 69; XXIX, 45, 56; XXXI, 38-9, 61-2; XXXII, 35; XXXV, 82
    Foster, Ben: XXIX, 3; XXXV, 107
    Foster, Charles: XXVII, 119; XXIX, 3
    Frankel, S: XXXVI, 89; XXXVII, 24-5
    Frazen, August: XXVII, 85, 99; XXXI, 73; XXXIII, 33; XXXV, 131; XXXVI, 23; XXXVIII, 36-40
    Freer, William Dink: XXX, 12; XXXV, 11, 39
    Friedlander, Arthur: XXXIII, 7
    Fuller, George: XXVI, 33; XXXI, 26; XXXV, 61
    Fury, C.: XXV, 23; XXVI, 33; XXVII, 119; XXIX, 68-9; XXXI, 11, 68; XXXII, 34
    Garber, Dan: XXVI, 46
    Gaspard, Leon: XXXVIII, 90-1
    Gay St.: XXXI, 65
    Gay, Edward: XXXI, 26, 49; XXXII, 4; XXXIII, 26, 31, 31, 33; XXXV, 45, 58
    Gay, Frank B.
    Gay, George A.
    Gernhardt, Harry: XXV, 103, 110; XXVII, 90; XXIX, 62; XXXI, 6
    Gerrity, Thos: XXVII, 38, 78, 80; XXIX, 49
    Gibson, Charles Dana: XXVI; XXXIII, 19, 25; XXXV B, 2-3
    Giles, Howard: XXVI, 97; XXVII, 101-2; XXIX, 6-8; XXXII, 4; XXXV, 107; XXXV B, 2, 4
    Golbberg, Frieda: XXXV B, 14-5, 15, 20-4
    Goldthwait, Anne: XXIX, 45; XXXV, 82
    Goodwin, Arthur: XXVI, 29; XXXI, 3-6; XXXVI, 22
    Gould, Robinson: XXXVIII, 41
    Grant, Isaac H.: XXV, 93
    Grant, Walter: XXXVIII, 20
    Granville-Smith, W.: XXVI, 104; XXVII, 38, 46, 68-9, 100-2; XXXII, 4; XXXIII, 19; XXXV, 78, 107, 116; XXXVIII, 9
    Greacen, Edward: XXIX, 55
    Green, Dulce: XXIX, 54
    Green, H. Abbot: XXV, 23; XXIX, 68; XXXI, 65
    Gregg, F. J.: XXVI, 98; XXVII, 32, 84-5, 90, 104-5; XXXII, 9
    Griffin, Walter: XXVII, 65, 71, 99-100, 115; XXIX, 58; XXX, 28; XXXI, 53; XXXIII, 34; XXXV, 81, 120